1938年9月，阿道夫·希特勒和法國，義大利及英國領袖在慕尼克舉行了一次會議
希特勒威脅，如果不把捷克斯洛伐克給德國就發動戰爭
面對並非盟友的德國，捷克斯洛伐克解除了其武裝力量
德國不費一槍一彈佔領了這個國家
一年以後，希特勒入侵波蘭，世界再次處於戰爭狀態
捷克斯洛伐克工廠對德國戰力極其重要
但生產遭到了反抗德國統治的抵抗力量的破壞
希特勒派遣了他的第三號人物，要粉碎任何針對納粹政權的抵抗力量
他名叫萊因哈德·海德里希
他因手段殘暴獲得了另一個名字
布拉格屠夫
本片基於真實事件拍攝
Where's the equipment?
裝備在哪？
Kurva!
婊子！
What happened?
發生了什麼？
Caught on one of the branches on
the way down. 在降落的時候 被一個樹枝掛到了
Can you walk?
能走嗎？
【類人猿行動】
You'll need stitches.
你需要縫針
Hey.
喂
You didn't hide your parachutes very well,
你們沒有把降落傘藏得很好啊
and you left a blood trail for
half a kilometer. 並且你留了一條半公里長的血腳印
Follow me.
跟我來
I live not far from here.
我住在不遠的地方
Dik! Come!
迪克（狗）！過來！
Ignac.
（人名）
Ignac!
（人名）！
Hot soup. Come.
有熱湯 來吧
Come in.
請進
I take it you are heading for Prague.
我想你們這是要去布拉格吧
How far is it?
有多遠呢？
Thirty kilometers.
30公里
I have a special delivery permit
for my truck. 我的卡車有一個運輸許可證（納粹頒發的）
I could take you.
我可以帶你們去
Thank you.
謝謝你
You rest here tonight.
你們今晚就在這裏休息吧
I will take you in the morning.
我明天一早就帶你們過去
Enjoy your soup.
好好享用你們的湯吧
Please, sit.
請坐
How much do the Germans pay you?
德國佬給你了多少錢?
For turning in your fellow countrymen, huh?
讓你供出同胞們?
Drop the gun.
扔掉槍
I said, drop the gun.
我說 扔掉槍
Drop it.
扔了
Drop the gun!
扔掉槍！
Gun.
槍
You get him?
你幹掉他了嗎？
We'll take that truck.
我們就開那輛卡車吧
Come on.
來吧
They had made their choice, Jan.
他們做了自己的選擇 楊
Sometimes you have to pick a side.
有些時候 人需要選邊站
Would you prefer it was us?
你希望他們選擇我們這一邊嗎？
Should be the next left.
應該是前一個路口左拐
Pull over here.
在這裏停吧
Mirek, come away from the window.
米瑞克 不要站在窗口
Anna, get the door!
安娜 去開門！
Yes?
有什麼是嗎？
We are looking for Oldrich Novak.
我們找歐德裏希·諾瓦克
The Novakovi no longer live here.
他們不住在這了
Who is it?
誰在門口呢？
Just somebody looking for directions.
就是有人在問路呢
I am sorry, but that's all I know.
不好意思 但這是我知道的全部了
Please.
請你等等
Can you help us?
可以給我們幫幫忙嗎？
There is a veterinarian in the next row
of shops up the street. 在街上第二排店舖里有一家獸醫診所
I hear he is a good man.
我聽說他是個好心人
One that may help.
他也許會幫助你們的
Thank you.
感謝你
He normally only barks at Germans.
他一般只對德國人汪汪
Mmm-mmm. Germans and anyone giving him a
rectal examination. 呵呵 除了德國人還有給他做直腸檢查的人
Thank you, Dr. Eduard.
謝謝你 愛德華醫生
Come along, Benes.
快給我過來 本尼希
Look after him, Mrs. Lukešova.
好好照顧他 路科索娃太太
Normally, for a dog bite,
一般來說 被狗咬了
you would go to a hospital, not a vet.
你應該去一家醫院 而不是獸醫診所
Did you know Oldrich Novak?
你認識歐德裏希·諾瓦克嗎？
Yes.
是的
And what if we were to say that
Oldrich Novak 如果我們說歐德裏希·諾瓦克
was our contact here in Prague?
是我們在布拉格的聯絡人呢？
Then I would have to wonder
那麼我就要開始考慮
if you are ill-informed Czech patriots
你們是不是消息不靈通的捷克憤青
or Gestapo spies 或者是蓋世太保的探子
trying to infiltrate what remains
of the resistance. 想要滲透進剩餘的抵抗組織裏
I don't detect a German accent.
我聽不出來你們有德國口音
The decoding papers in your bag,
那些在你包裏的解密手冊
they don't have a German font.
沒有德文在上面
And given that this wound
然後通過你的這個傷口
has more tree bark than dog bite,
比起狗的咬傷 看起來更像是樹的掛傷
I would have to guess 我不禁要猜一猜
that you were parachuted back
into Czechoslovakia 你是跳傘潛入的捷克斯洛伐克
with information that was somewhat
out of date. 並且掌握的情報已經過時了
You're a clever man.
你真是一個聰明人
We were also told you were a good man.
我們也聽說你是一個好人
How long have you been away?
你們離開捷克斯洛伐克多久了?
It's been a while.
有段日子了
Rewards are given to people who inform
on anti-Nazi activity. 現在懸賞提供反納粹活動的人
Heydrich has all but crushed the
resistance. 海因裏希差不多已經把抵抗組織消滅殆盡了
He has executed thousands.
他處決了上千人
I can put you in contact with the miller.
我可以幫你聯繫上磨坊（代號）
Maybe he can help you.
也許他可以幫助你
You can stay here tonight.
你們今晚可以呆在這裏
I'll contact the miller in the morning.
我明天一早就會聯繫磨坊
My friend here says 我朋友剛說
that you are a clever man.
你是一個聰明人
I agree.
我很贊同
Don't do anything that would change
our opinion. 千萬不要做任何改變我這看法的傻事
Go easy on the foot.
少用一點這隻腳
You will be dancing the tango
within a week. 你一周後就能跳探戈舞了
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
喂 喂 喂...
This is Břetislav.
這是佈雷特斯拉夫
The miller.
代號磨坊
EDUARD told me you were looking for
Oldrich Novak. 愛德華告訴我你們在找歐德裏希·諾瓦克
Yes.
是的
Would you like to take a drive with me?
你們能跟我上車走一趟嗎？
Don't move.
別動
Please sit.
請坐
You were looking for Oldrich Novak.
你們在找歐德裏希·諾瓦克
Who gave you this contact?
誰給你的這個聯繫人？
London.
倫敦的人
And you tell us this because?
你為什麼告訴我？
You are not giving us much choice
你們不給我們留餘地
and this doesn't look like Gestapo
headquarters. 並且這裏看起來也不像蓋世太保的總部（所以我們就告訴你咯）
You, where are you from?
你 從哪裏來？
Your accent, Bohemia?
你的口音是波西米亞的嗎？
No, Dolni Vilemovice, Moravia.
不 Dolni Vilemovice 摩拉維亞
So you must know the railway station
at Vladislav? 所以你肯定知道弗拉迪斯拉夫的火車站咯？
Yes.
是的
What's so special about it?
那有什麼特別的地方嗎？
I presume you are talking about the large
bed of colored roses 我猜你是想說那個由彩色的玫瑰組成的
that when seen from above is in the shape
of our national flag? 從上面看起來就像我們國旗形狀的巨大花床嗎？
Is it still there?
它還在那嗎？
Seems the Germans have still not looked
at it from above. 看起來德國人還沒有從上面觀察過它
I am Vanek.
我是范尼克
Ladislav Vanek.
拉迪斯拉夫·范尼克
This is Uncle Hajsky.
這是海斯基叔叔
We are the head of the Jindra Organization.
我們是金德拉組織的領導
Czech resistance.
捷克抵抗力量
I am Jan Kubiš.
我是楊·克比奇
I am Josef Gabčik.
我是約瑟夫·加布切克
From Slovakia.
斯洛伐克來的
You must not be surprised by our
lack of trust. 你肯定對我們的多疑不感奇怪
The Gestapo have been very successful in
infiltrating our network. 蓋世太保很成功的打入了我們組織的內部
Oldrich Novak.
歐德裏希·諾瓦克
He was taken away several months ago.
他已經被抓走了好幾個月了
Why wasn't London informed?
倫敦怎麼一點消息都沒有？
We lost Contact with the Czech
government in exile 我們已經和捷克在倫敦的流亡政府
in London some months ago.
失去聯繫好幾個月了
We need replacement crystals for
the transmitter. 我們需要給發報機更換晶體
We've been waiting for them to send someone
我們一直在等他們派人過來
to re-establish contact.
重新建立起聯絡
Is that you?
是你嗎？
There were other men on the plane.
在飛機上還有其他的人
They were dropped elsewhere.
他們在別處降落了
It's possible they have orders
他們可能執行重建與倫敦聯繫的任務
to re-establish contact
with London but that... 但是
That is not our mission.
那不是我們的任務
What is your mission?
你們的任務是什麼呢？
Operation Anthropoid.
類人猿行動
Anthropoid?
類人猿？
What is Anthropoid?
類人猿是什麼？
We are here to assassinate
我們是來刺殺
SS Obergruppenfuhrer Reinhard Heydrich.
黨衛軍參謀總長 蓋世太保頭子 波西米亞總督萊因哈德·海德裏希
Are you completely mad?
你們完全瘋掉了嗎？
We have our orders, comrade. But this
is madness. 約瑟夫：我們有命令在身 同志 范尼克：但這是瘋狂的行為
We have our orders, comrade.
我們有命令在身 同志
Heydrich?
海德裏希？
Why stop with Heydrich?
為什麼只殺海德裏希一個呢？
Why not have a go at Hitler as well?
為什麼不連希特勒也一起幹掉算了？
He is only 300 kilometers down the road
他就在只有300公里開外
in a small village called Berlin.
一個叫柏林的一個小村子裏
So we inform London
這樣的話 我們只好聯繫倫敦
that you are refusing to cooperate
with our mission. 告訴他們你拒絕為我們這次任務提供協助咯？
How dare you question us?
你竟敢質疑我們？
You know what we have sacrificed for
the cause here? 你知道我們為這裏所犧牲的一切嗎？
What you have sacrificed?
你們犧牲了什麼？
What has Czechoslovakia sacrificed?
捷克斯洛伐克犧牲了什麼？
You have no idea what we've sacrificed!
你完全不知道我們做出了怎樣的犧牲！
Sit down. Please.
請坐下
You kill Heydrich 你殺了海德裏希的話
and Hitler will tear Prague apart.
希特勒會把布拉格撕爛
I take it you have family in
Czechoslovakia? 我相信你在捷克斯洛伐克有親人？
Father? Mother?
爸爸？媽媽？
You kill Heydrich, 你殺了海德裏希的話
then you can consider them and everyone that
ever knew you dead. 你可以認為你的父母和所有你認識的人都會死去
All Czech patriots 所有的捷克愛國認識
should be ready to die for their country.
都應該做好為國家犧牲的準備
That includes my family.
這也包括了我的家庭
Well, I'm not.
行 但是不包括我的家庭
I want to carry on fighting.
我想要一直戰鬥下去
We don't have that many left that are
willing to do that. 我們剩下的想要去抗爭的人已經不多了
We are what's left of the Czech resistance.
我們是捷克抵抗組織所剩不多的力量了
I suggest a lesser rank should be
assassinated. 我建議刺殺一個級別低一點的目標吧
Perhaps a few of them.
也許可以刺殺幾個這樣的目標
Heydrich is the head of the secret police.
海德裏希是蓋世太保的頭子
Only Hitler and Himmler are above him in the Nazi
hierarchy. 只有希特勒和希姆萊在納粹黨的地位比他高（帝國空軍元帥戈林表示不服）
Exactly my point.
我就是這麼考慮的
You really think you'll ever get close enough
to assassinate Heydrich? 你真以為你會有機會靠近海德裏希去刺殺他嗎？
Our orders have come direct from the Czech
government in London. 我們的命令是直接從倫敦的捷克斯洛伐克政府下達的
So this is about the Czech
government in London 所以說這就是倫敦的捷克政府
trying to impress the allies?
想要通過這來跪舔盟軍咯？
It was the allies that gave us to the Germans in
the first place. 正是盟軍在一開始把我們拱手送給了德國人（慕尼黑協定出賣了捷克）
Munich was a betrayal, 慕尼黑是一個背叛
but it is also now history.
但那已經成為了歷史
I think what the Czech government in London
我想在倫敦的流亡政府
is asking is this.
目的是在於想要明白
Is Czechoslovakia 是否捷克斯洛伐克
still ready and willing to resist
Nazi Germany? 仍然準備並且希望去抵抗納粹德國？
Josef Gabčik.
約瑟夫·加布切克
And Jan Kubiš.
和楊·庫比奇
You are both most welcome here.
十分歡迎你們兩個
And please call me Auntie Moravec.
請叫我莫拉維斯阿姨
Ata. Ata.
阿提亞 阿提亞
Ata is my son.
阿提亞是我兒子
He is studying to be a violinist.
他正在學習成為一個小提琴手
Ata, this is Josef and this is Jan.
阿提亞 這是約瑟夫 這是楊
Pleased to meet you both.
很高興見到你們兩個
So, try not to go outside,
所以 盡量不要嘗試去外面
but if you do, never walk together.
但是如果你們必須出去的話 千萬不要走一起
If you're stopped, 如果你被攔下的話
you will need an excuse for why you're
not at work. 你需要準備一個為什麼你沒有在工作的理由
We'll try to get you medical certificates
as soon as possible. 我們會盡快給你們弄到病假條
Always use our code, 永遠接的我們的接頭暗號
three knocks, then a single knock.
連敲三下 再單敲一下
In the meantime, 同時
lay low and I will use Ata to make contact.
保持低調 我會通過阿提亞和你們聯繫
Good luck.
祝你們好運
Thank you.
謝謝你
Goodbye.
再見
Come on through, please.
請進來吧
Josef 約瑟夫
There is a way off the roof?
房頂上有路可以下去嗎？
There is a fire escape to the left.
在左側有一個防火通道
To the right it continues to the
building next door. 在右側連著隔壁的房子
It's good enough.
足夠好了
I'm sure you both would like a
glass of Becherovka. 我想你們想要一杯冰爵利口酒
Thank you.
麻煩你了
- It's okay. 沒事的
- Mrs. Moravec? 莫拉維斯太太？
Hey.你好
There was so much people at the market.
剛剛在市場人特別的多
But I didn't find the bread that you like.
但是我沒找到你想要的那一款麵包
Come.
過來吧
Who is it? 他們是誰？
It's okay, Marie. 沒事的 瑪利亞
This is Josef and this is Jan.
這位是約瑟夫 這位是楊
They will be staying with us
他們在找工作的期間
while they are looking for work.
會與我們住在一起.
Pleased to meet you. 很高興見到你
Hello. 你好呀
Hello. 你好
Josef and Jan are not registered
with the police 約瑟夫和楊還沒有去公安局
as being residents here, 上布拉格的戶口
so, remember, please keep it strictly
to yourself. 所以請你一定要記住 保守好這個秘密
I'll put the shopping in the kitchen.
我把買的東西放到廚房去
Welcome.
歡迎你們
Mrs. Kovarnikova's daughter. I pay her
for helping out. 她是庫尼科瓦先生的女兒我們雇她過來幫忙
Dinner will be at 6:00.
晚飯在6點鐘好
Please sit.
請坐
Ata, dinner is ready.
阿提亞 晚飯做好了
And finally the fiddler is silent.
終於拉琴的夥計安靜了
He is a violinist, Alois. A violinist.
他是一名小提琴演奏家 阿洛依斯 演奏家不是拉琴的
You two boys looking for work, then?
那你們兩個小伙子是在找工作咯？
Yes.
是的
We are always looking for men to clean the
cinders out of the locomotives. 我們一直在招人清理火車頭裏的煤渣
Thank you, Mr. Moravec.
謝謝你 莫拉維斯先生
We'll keep that in mind.
我們會記著的
So, what do you do when you aren't
helping out here? 所以說 你不在這裏幫忙的時候 一般幹嘛呢？
You don't have a boyfriend?
你沒有男朋友嗎？
No.
沒有
How's life in occupied Prague, Marie?
在布拉格淪陷區的生活如何呢 瑪利亞？
I guess, not being registered with
the police as residents 我猜沒有去警察局上戶口
has something to do with this question?
和我平時在幹嗎有關聯咯？
I hate the Germans.
我厭惡德國人
And tell me, 那麼告訴我
do you have a friend 你有沒有一個
as lovely as you that...
和你同樣可愛的朋友呢...
That you can trust?
你可以信任的朋友？
Why?
為什麼這麼問？
It would be less conspicuous if Jan and I were
not seen out alone. 我和楊有女伴出門的話 會看起來比較不那麼可疑
Young love flourishes under
German occupation. 盛開在德占區天真爛漫的情侶
That sort of thing.
就要的那種感覺
But you're not that young.
但是你看起來不是那麼的年輕
Knowing that you are trustworthy is
one thing, Marie. 我們知道你是可靠的人是一方面 瑪利亞
But doing this could get you shot.
但是和我們假扮情侶的話 有可能會吃槍子
Perhaps you should think about it...
也許你應該考慮一下...
My friend, Lenka.
我有個朋友 蘭卡
She sometimes carries messages
for Uncle Hajsky. 她有時候替海斯基叔叔傳遞消息
Good.
很好
We are going to a New Year's Eve
dance tomorrow night. 我們明晚回去一個新年舞會
Would you like to go?
你們想要一起去嗎？
Look at them.
看看他們
It's like...
就像...
It's like some old ritual that's
lost its joy. 就像某種失去樂趣的過時社交活動
Maybe there's hope in the pretense.
也許在虛偽的同胞裏還是有希望的
Hello.
你好
It looks like you've landed on your
feet with Lenka. 看起來你沒有被蘭卡放鴿子呀
This was a mistake.
她們犯了個錯誤
Hello.
你好
Lenka, this is Jan and Josef.
蘭卡 這是楊和約瑟夫
You know, it's not very polite... 知道嗎
你不站起來很沒禮貌... Please sit down. 請坐下
You are the most beautiful women
in the room. 你是這大廳裏最漂亮的女士
Congratulations.
祝賀你
But you fail to understand this is...
但是你完全沒有明白
This is not a night off for us.
今晚不是我們娛樂的時間
This is not some game.
這不是個兒戲
Josef, maybe you're overreacting
a little... 約瑟夫 也許你有點神經過敏了...
Jan, take a look around.
楊 看看四周
We appreciate the effort, but the point was not
to attract attention. 我們感謝你們的努力 但今晚重點是不要吸引大多注意力
We needed you as plain as possible.
我們需要你們盡可能的打扮的普通點
Do you understand?
你明白嗎？
You know, for most girls,
你知道嗎 對於大多數的女生
a little lipstick is the only way to forget
一個小小的口紅是唯一能使我們
what's happening here.
忘記現實的東西
Even if it's just for a few hours.
即使是僅僅幾個小時而已
Yes.
是的
Your lipstick gets you noticed,
你的口紅讓你備受矚目
and that gets us noticed,
這也讓我們大家被注意到
and us being noticed gets us all shot.
然後我們被盯上的話 會讓我們都吃槍子兒
This little scene needs an ending.
現在這個局面必須趕緊結束
Slap my face.
打我一耳光
I'm not a whore.
我不是個婊子
I think that went well.
我覺得我們大家相處的真不錯
Nine... Eight... Seven...
9..8..7..
Six... Five... Four... Three... Two... One.
6... 5... 4... 3... 2...1
A British Sten Mark II machine gun.
英國斯登二型衝鋒鎗一把
One hundred rounds.
100發子彈
And Model 73 anti-tank grenades
with pencil fuses. 幾個延時引信的73型反坦克手雷
That's everything we could retrieve from the
drop canister. 這是我們能從空投圓筒（片頭那個）裏拿到的全部東西了
Uncle says he has made some progress
海叔說對於你想要瞭解的情報
with the information you asked for.
他取得了一些進展
There is a meeting at Cafe Moravia on
Vodičkova Street. 我們會在沃迪科瓦街的摩拉維亞咖啡館開會
Tuesday. 2:00.
週二 下午兩點
I just wanted to apologize about
the other night. 我想為我那晚的行為向你道歉
You were completely right to
do what you did. 你那晚的行為是完全正確的
Marie didn't fully inform me about
the situation. 瑪利亞之前沒有告訴我那晚的全部情況
She is very young, 她太年輕了
she still has romantic ideas about the war.
對於戰爭還是抱有浪漫的幻想
And you?
那你呢？
War is not romantic.
戰爭可一點都不浪漫
We cross here.
我們在這過馬路
After our last date, 在上次的約會之後
I thought you might both show wearing
potato sacks. 我覺得你們會穿裝土豆的袋子來見我們了
I don't know what I'm doing.
我不知道自己做的對不對
You are doing fine.
你做的可以了
Take a seat here. Order a drink.
在這裏坐下 點一杯喝的
We won't be long.
我們不會太久
Josef.
約瑟夫
- Jan. 楊
- Opalka. 歐帕卡
Valčik.
瓦切克
I see you are no strangers to one another,
我想你們應該都認識
but we don't have much time.
但是我們時間不多了
We all trained special operations together.
我們在特種作戰的訓練時在一起上課
Valčik here was even on the same drop.
瓦切克還是和我們同一批空降的呢
Yes, dropped 10 minutes later and 30 miles
off course. 是啊 比你們晚了十分鐘 結果偏離預定地點了30公里 呵呵
Thanks to Valčik and his group Silver A,
感謝瓦切克和他的銀A小組
we have finally re-established
communications with London. 我們終於重新和倫敦建立起了聯繫
I have orders to send and receive
any communications 我被命令要求收發
between you and London.
你和倫敦之間的所有通訊
You have your own decoder book, right?
你帶了自己的解密手冊對嗎?
Yes.
是的
Second Lieutenant Opalka and
Warrant Officer Curda 歐帕卡少尉和庫達准尉
have completed Operation Out Distance,
已經完成了[超距]行動
so both are now available to assist you.
所以他們現在都可以協助你們了
Second Lieutenant Opalka is the
senior officer here. 少尉歐帕卡是這裏的高級軍官了
Yes, this is true, 是的 這是事實
but your mission objective supersedes
my rank. 但你任務的優先級是凌駕於我的軍銜之上的
We had word from London. Anthropoid.
我們收到了倫敦的回話了 [類人猿]行動
Utmost priority.
有最高優先級
We assist with everything possible.
我們要竭盡全力的協助你們
So...
這樣的話...
This is your show, bratři.
就看你們的表演了, 兄弟
So, we know that Heydrich returns
to his family 那麼 我們目前知道海德裏希每天
every day at Panenske Břežany.
回到帕內斯克的家裏
But, both his chateau and the castle are both
heavily guarded. 但他家裏的莊園和辦公的堡壘都處於戒備森嚴的狀態
They are not feasible targets.
他們不是可行的目標
But once a month, 但是每一個月
he also travels to Berlin, by train.
他都會乘火車去一次柏林
And we can predict this
我們可以據此預判他的出行
because his personal carriages are prepared
several days in advance. 因為他的乘坐的車廂會提前幾天準備好
But, again, the station and the train are both
heavily guarded. 但還是同樣的 火車站和火車廂都會處於戒備森嚴的狀態
What about derailing the train outside
of Prague? 那在布拉格郊外讓他的火車脫軌怎麼樣？
We can derail the train,
我們可以把他的火車弄脫軌
but that is no guarantee that
Heydrich is killed. 但那並不能保證海德裏希一定會被殺死
I have made contact with an
ex-pupil of mine 我和我之前的學生聯繫上了
who works as a repair man
inside the castle. 他現在堡壘裏的做修理工
He's willing to help, 他願意給我們提供幫助
but he only knows when Heydrich arrives
in the morning 但是他只能知道海德裏希早上到達的時間
and when he leaves.
和他下班離開的時間
What good is that?
這能起到什麼作用？
You can build a picture
你可以此建立起一張
of his routine.
他的作息時間表
Sometimes he travels with an armed escort and
sometimes he does not. 有時候有輛裝甲車護送他 有時候沒有
Perhaps there is a pattern in this.
也許這裏面有規律可循
There is a safe house near the castle.
我們在堡壘旁邊 有一個藏身處
The repairman could drop off the timetable
every day before work. 那個修理工每天上班之前都能送海德裏希的時間表
Lenka or Marie could collect it.
蘭卡或者瑪利亞能去取一下
Good.
很好
And Jan and I will follow the route
然後楊和我會盯著他
from the chateau to the castle.
從莊園到堡壘的路線
Gentlemen, 先生們
this operation 這個行動
will involve almost everyone we have
left in the resistance. 將會需要我們抵抗組織的每一名成員
So many have been captured by the Gestapo.
已經有太多的同志們被蓋世太保逮捕了
If you are arrested, 如果你被捕的話
you will face some harsh facts.
你將會面臨一些殘酷的現實
There will be no escape.
你將不可能會逃跑
You'll be tortured until you reveal
everything you know, 你會被嚴刑拷打直到吐出你知道的一切
and then you will be executed.
然後你就會被處決
You must protect your fellow comrades
你必須保護其他的同志們
by shutting down any links you have
to them. 通過切斷和他們的一切聯繫（暗示就算自殺也不能被捕）
Operation Out Distance has re-supplied
us with these. [超距]行動給我們重新補充了這些
Carry the cyanide capsules at all times.
隨身攜帶好這些氰化物膠囊
We have to end our meeting.
我們需要結束這次會議了
Use the window.
從窗戶走
Clear.
安全了
Looks like there's a whole garrison there.
看起來那裏有一整個衛戍兵團
That's our man.
這就是我們的目標
Five minutes after 9:00.
上午9點過五分
He's riding solo today.
他今天一個人開車
Wait.
等等
Armed escort.
裝甲車
Thirty seconds behind.
相距30秒鐘
Thirty seconds.
30秒
Thirty seconds, 30 seconds.
30秒鐘呀
If we can use a rope 如果我們能用跟繩子
or a steel cable to stop the Mercedes,
或者是一根鋼索把奔馳停下來
then 30 seconds...
然後30秒之內...
Then 30 seconds would be all we need.
然後30秒鐘就夠了
Even if a rope can stop the car,
即使一根繩子可以把車停下來
we still need more than 30 seconds to
escape from here. 我們仍然需要超過30秒鐘的時間來逃跑
And we'd have to face the armed guard
here in the open. 並且我們不得不在這個開闊地帶面對衛戍武裝
It would not be my first choice.
這並不是我的最好的選擇
And if it's our only choice?
但是如果這是我們唯一的選擇呢？
The point of the mission is to succeed.
Yes? 這個行動的目的就是要成功刺殺海德裏希 對嗎？
I'm more worried that 我更擔心的是
we haven't planned what to do if we
are successful. 我們還沒準備好在任務成功之後應該怎麼逃跑
What happens afterwards is not important.
之後發生什麼 無關痛癢了（要提高自己的思想覺悟）
Let's follow the route to the castle.
讓我們沿著這條路去堡壘吧
Well?
怎麼樣？
Arrived 9:15, left 5:15,
9點15分到達 5點15分離開（這麼高軍級 勞模啊）
with an armed escort.
有一輛裝甲車護送
Armed escort?
裝甲車？
There's only one person in Prague
在布拉格只有一個人
that travels with an armed escort.
有裝甲車護送
Are you going to assassinate Heydrich?
你們是要去刺殺海德裏希嗎？
What?
什麼？
Heydrich is the target?
目標是海德裏希？
For your own safety, 為了你們自身的安全
it's best that you don't ask too
many questions. 你們最好不要問太多的問題了
It's a bit too late for that now.
你說這句話是不是有點晚了
Well, you agreed to help the resistance.
好吧 是你自己同意幫助抵抗組織的
Who the target is should not concern you.
你不應該關心誰是目標
We are about to help you assassinate
Reinhard Heydrich. 我們馬上要幫助你們刺殺萊因哈德·海德裏希了
- Of course it concerns us. 我們當然要關心了
- Okay. 好吧
Everyone just relax.
大家都放鬆一下
Maybe it was a mistake not to inform
you of the danger. 也許是我們的錯誤沒有提醒你們其中的危險
- Murder Heydrich? 謀殺海德裏希？
- No, no. 不對 不對
Assassinate Heydrich.
刺殺海德裏希
Murder implies he has a life worth living.
謀殺這個詞帶有他是無辜的意思
So you think we are just two little girls
所以你認為我們就是兩個
who are here to follow the important
parachutists around? 無條件服從空降兵特工的小女孩咯？
Whoa. Lenka.
好嘛 蘭卡
We've been resisting here from the beginning
in our own way. 我們已經從一開始就用自己方式在抵抗了
I personally don't have any reservation to
killing a Nazi pig. 我個人來說的話 對殺掉某個納粹雜種是沒有任何保留的
But don't treat us like what
you are about to do 但是不要把我們當做
doesn't affect us.
你們這件事的後果對我們一點影響都沒有
It does and it will.
這件事必然也將會對你們造成影響
And you should keep your weapon clean
because it's filthy. 你應該保持你武器的清潔 因為它太髒了
Marie?
瑪利亞？
Where are all my pots and pans?
我的那些瓶瓶罐罐呢？
This exit here, is this.
出口在這
You see?
你看見了嗎？
It's the slowest part of the route.
這是在這條路線裏 最慢的一段
Anywhere else is impossible.
除了這兒 其他的地方都不可能
So we do it here.
那麼我們在這動手吧
Agreed?
同意嗎？
Yes.
行
Perhaps not perfect, but it's the
best option. 也許這不是最完美的 但也是最好的辦法了
Good.
很好
9:17 to 4:41.
9點17分到4點41分
Without.
沒有帶裝甲車
Are you really going to go
through with this? 你們真的要這樣幹嗎？
We have our orders.
我們有命令在身吶
So, you kill Heydrich.
那麼 你殺了海德裏希
What then?
然後會怎麼樣？
You think there aren't more like him?
你覺得不會有很多和他一樣的人嗎？
They come and the killing continues
他們會被調過來 然後殺戮還將繼續
even worse than it did before.
也許比現在還要糟糕
When does it stop?
這將何時會停止？
I wish I had an answer for you.
我希望我能回答你這個問題
You think any of this makes sense to me?
你認為我會想得通這些嗎？
Then walk away now.
那麼現在趕緊走吧
And go where, Marie?
瑪利亞 能走去哪呢
You think we can escape from what is
happening here? 你認為我們能逃得出這裏發生的一切嗎？
Pretend this madness is not real?
裝作這瘋狂的一切不是真的？
Some days I'm not even sure it is real.
有些時候 我甚至不確定這是真的
Heydrich chokes the people of this city with
a blanket of fear. 海德裏希用恐怖織成的毯子 悶死著布拉格的人民
People are shot for what?
人們為什麼被槍決？
Their race? Their religion? Their
cigarettes? 他們的種族？ 他們的信仰？他們抽煙？
You hear the stories about Poland.
你聽過波蘭那邊的故事嗎？（集中營 屠殺猶太人）
Marie, it's okay.
瑪利亞 沒事的
Just tell me we are doing the right thing.
你就告訴我 我們這麼做是正確的
I think it is my turn to apologize to you about
the other morning. 我覺得現在應該輪到我為那天早晨的事向你道歉了
You were right to be angry.
你的憤怒是正確的
We should have told you what was at risk.
我們應該告訴你有哪些危險
Given you the choice to walk away.
給你選擇離開的機會
My father was a captain in the army.
我爸爸之前是陸軍上尉
Wanted sons, got three daughters.
一直想要兒子 卻得到了三個女兒
He and many others were arrested in '39
當德國控制了捷克斯洛伐克之後
when Germany took control over
Czechoslovakia. 他和許多其他的人在1939年被逮捕了
And when Heydrich took over here
last September, 然後當海德裏希於去年9月在這裏掌權之後
his first order was to execute all
the prisoners. 他的第一個命令 就是處決所有的犯人
My father was among 5,000 shot in the first
week by Heydrich. 我的爸爸在頭一個星期處決的那5000人裏
For me there's no walking away.
對於我來說 已近不存在什麼放棄不放棄了
Heydrich is worth the risk.
我值得為刺殺海德裏希冒這個險
We have checked the route.
我們已近檢查過他平時的路線了
We think we know how to do it.
我們認為我們知道該怎麼做了
I will arrange a meeting.
我會安排一次會議
At the cafe, the day after tomorrow.
後天在那家咖啡館
3:00 p.m.
下午三點鐘
Our original contact, 我們最初的聯繫人
Oldrich Novak.
歐德裏希·諾瓦克
Who was his direct handler?
誰是他頂頭上司？
Ladislav Vanek.
拉迪斯拉夫·范尼克
He is the one who's most opposed to
what we have to do. 他就是那個最反對我們刺殺任務的人
All I'm asking is what is he so afraid of?
我就想問一問 他在那麼害怕什麼？
Jan?
楊？
Sorry.
不好意思
So he approaches here.
所以當他往這兒來
Corner of Kirchmayer and Holeschowitzer
Street. 在克奇邁爾瓦街和霍勒斯維策爾街的交叉口
Here.
這裏
Yes, his car will have to really slow down
to take that corner. 是的 他的車通過那個路口的時候會開的特別慢
Yes, he slows to about 10 miles per hour.
是的 當他會降到差不多10英里每小時
We've averaged out his morning
arrival times. 我們已經平均計算出了他早上到達的大概時間
We can expect him at approximately
9:30 a.m. 我們能預計他在將近上午9點30分到那裏
And the weapons?
那麼武器是什麼呢？
At that range the Sten gun should hit everything
within the car. 在那個距離下 斯登衝鋒鎗應該能射穿車裏的一切
And the armed escort?
那輛裝甲車呢？
We have found no pattern.
我們還沒找出它的規律
Some days, yes. Some days, no.
有時候有 有時候沒有
If there is an armed escort,
如果正好有裝甲車的話
we stand down and await the next day.
我們不要動手 等到下一次再說
You know I have been against this
action from the start. 你知道我從一開始就不同意這個行動
Yes, that's been clear.
是的 這是顯而易見的
I cannot give the go-ahead
我不能在沒有要求倫敦三思的情況下
without asking London to reconsider.
讓你們去執行這次任務
Ladislav, this is a military operation. It's not
your order to give... 拉迪斯拉夫 這是一次軍事行動你無權下達命令...
Without the resistance, this mission
doesn't exist. 沒有抵抗組織的協助 這次任務是不可能完成的
Do you want to put...
你是想要...
I am with Ladislav.
我同意拉迪斯拉夫
We should get London to rethink
our position 我們需要讓倫敦根據布拉格的實際情況
here in Prague.
在考慮一下
We have our orders, Curda. And nothing
has changed. 我們有自己的命令 庫達 計劃照常進行
It's easy for London to give orders.
倫敦下達命令倒是輕鬆
It's our lives on the line...
我們在這裏賣命...
Let's wait for re-confirmation.
讓我們等著再確認一次吧
We waited four months.
我們已經等待了4個月了
Four months.
4個月啊
London needs action.
倫敦需要我們行動了
Then a few more days won't make
a difference. 那麼再多等幾天也不會有很大的改變
Valčik, how long before you can get
to the transmitter? 瓦切克 你多久能把發報機準備好？
I can get to the transmitter the
day after tomorrow. 我能在後天準備好
Then a couple of days for London to
transmit back the answer. 那麼還需要再過幾天來收到倫敦的回復
Happy birthday.
生日快樂
Happy birthday. 生日快樂！
Happy birthday, Ata. 生日快樂 阿提亞！
Thank you. 謝謝你們
Cheers. 乾杯
Cheers.
乾杯
It's beautiful. 這真漂亮
Thank you. 謝謝你
Uh...
嗯...
Ata, I know this is your party,
阿提亞 我知道這是你的生日聚會
but we have a little announcement to make.
但是我們有一個小小的通告要宣佈
I have asked Marie to marry me and
she has said yes. 我已經向瑪利亞求婚了 而且她答應了我
Congratulations.
恭喜
- Congratulations. 恭喜你
- Thank you. 謝謝
Thank you. 感謝
Congratulations. 恭喜
Thank you. 謝謝你
Why are we here?
我們在這裏幹嘛的？
Hmm?
額？
I know.
我知道
Who's to say it won't happen?
誰說這不會發生
London calls it off.
倫敦取消了這次行動
You're lying to yourself, my friend.
你在自欺欺人 朋友
Because it is easier.
因為這要容易些
I have to believe there is a way
through this. 我需要相信這件事情一定有出路
That there is a normal life waiting for us.
有一個普通人的生活在等著我們
The way things used to be.
就像過去的時候一樣
Marie makes me feel that there is hope.
瑪利亞讓我感到了有希望
I love her.
我愛她
I do. I love her.
我真的很愛他
I had the idea to transfer the 73
我有一個用水壺裝73號手雷提高
into a water canteen for better mobility.
便攜性的改裝點子
Rigged for impact detonation.
用碰撞來引爆它
Don't drop them, eh?
那就不要把它們掉地上了 啊？
That was the empty one.
這個是空的
No, not funny, Jan.
一點也不好笑 楊
Not funny.
一點也不
"Anthropoid proceed.
類人猿行動繼續
"Stop.
停止
"Upmost importance."
最重要
Nothing about getting us out afterwards.
沒有任何在之後把我們弄出去的內容嗎
There's a problem.
出了一個問題
One of our contacts inside the castle has
seen correspondence 我們其中一個聯繫人在堡壘裏看到了
ordering Heydrich back to Berlin.
命令海德裏希回柏林的信件
And there have been conversations
in the household 然後還有一些關於在巴黎的
about a new posting to Paris.
一個新崗位的對話
It means that once he goes to Berlin,
這意味著他一旦回了柏林
he may not be back.
他也許將不會回來了
When does he leave?
他什麼時候出發離開呢？
Day after tomorrow.
後天
Then we have no choice.
那麼我們別無選擇了
We do it tomorrow.
我們明天就動手
What? What is it?
怎麼了 怎麼回事？
Ladislav has received a new transmission
from London. 拉迪斯拉夫收到了倫敦的信消息
And?
然後呢？
They agreed with my request to stand
down the mission. 他們同意了我取消這次行動的請求
We believe we see the situation clearly,
我相信我們把情況看的很清楚
therefore, given the situation,
所以根據這樣的情況
any actions against officials of
the German Reich 任何針對第三帝國官員的行動
do not come into consideration.
都不予以考慮
Let the Jindra group know.
讓金德拉組織知道
No.
不可能
Ladislav, 拉迪斯拉夫
I've just decoded a message from London.
我剛解碼了一份倫敦來的消息
"Proceed. Upmost importance."
"繼續. 最重要的."
But this clearly states you must
stand down. 但是我這封明確告訴你了要取消任務
You are deluded. This is for Jindra.
你被騙了 這是給金德拉的
So how can we recognize this?
所以我們怎麼樣才能識別它的真偽？
Then at least wait for us to clarify it.
那麼至少要等著我們來澄清它的真偽
It may have superseded your order.
這個消息也許取代了你的命令
We have no time.
我們沒時間了
After tomorrow Heydrich will be gone.
過了明天 海德裏希就要走了
I agree with Josef.
我同意約瑟夫的
I don't think this is a direct command.
我不認為這是一個直接的命令
I believe its purpose is to calm the
nerves in Jindra. 我相信這封消息的目的是要安撫金德拉內部緊張的神經
I know you all doubt me.
我知道你們都不信任我
No, Ladislav...沒有啊 拉迪斯拉夫...
Please stop. 請別解釋了
Suspect me of collaboration.
懷疑我通敵賣國
I know you've had me followed.
我知道你們派人跟蹤我了
I understand you don't trust me, but,
我理解你對我的不信任 但是
if I was an informer for the Gestapo,
如果我是蓋世太保的臥底
do you think you would still be here?
你覺得你為什麼還能站在這裏？
Do you?
你覺得呢？
Then you tell me, Ladislav.
那麼告訴我 拉迪斯拉夫
What are you afraid of?
你在害怕些什麼呢？
I fear Czechoslovakia will be wiped
from the map. 我害怕的是捷克斯洛伐克將被從地圖上永遠的抹去
You ask me if I'm afraid?
你問我是否害怕呢？
Yes, I'm afraid.
是的 我害怕
Jan, Uncle, we do it tomorrow.
楊 海叔 我們明天動手
As planned.
按計劃的來
May God be with you.
希望上帝保佑你
Jan.
楊
I've shot at men in the field. Never
killed one up close. 我在陣地上朝人射擊過 從沒在近距離殺過人
Give me the gun. Give me the gun.
把槍給我把槍給我
- I don't want to die tomorrow. 我明天不想死
- Give me the gun. 把槍給我
Breathe. Breathe.
深呼吸深呼吸
Now...
現在...
Thank you, Mrs. Moravec. Thank you.
謝謝你 莫拉維斯太太謝謝你
Okay. Breathe. Breathe.
好的深呼吸 深呼吸
Breathe. Breathe, Jan.
深呼吸 深呼吸 楊
Good.
好的
Now, as we were trained.
現在 就像我們之前訓練的一樣
As we were trained. Concentrate on
the detail. 就像我們訓練的一樣 把注意力集中在細節上
Good.
很好
We are not afraid.
我們不害怕
Jan, we are not afraid.
楊 我們不害怕
Czechoslovakia is not afraid.
捷克斯洛伐克不害怕
Huh?
嗯？
I will wait for you up the street.
我會在街上等你
Uncle said we weren't needed for a while.
海叔告訴我 我們一段時間內都不用過來了
Is it today?
你們是不是今天動手
Promise me.
向我保證（活著回來）
We have plenty of time.
我們時間足夠
8:25.
8點25分
Where's Curda?
庫達在哪裏?
Never mind.
無所謂了
Valčik, you take this street behind me.
瓦切克 你去我後面的這條街
We have some sun, so take this.
今天有陽光 所以拿著這個
If he approaches without an armed escort,
如果他過來的時候 沒有裝甲車的話
then use it to signal.
用這個發信息
And if he does?
如果有裝甲車呢？
Then... Then light a cigarette.
那麼點一根煙
When the car slows to take the corner,
當他的車減速過路口的時候
I will step out and open fire
with the Sten gun. 我會衝出來用斯登槍開火
This will signal the attack.
這就是動手的信號
Jan, you stand behind the attack point
楊 你等在我的後面
so you can throw grenades at the armed
escort if there is one. 如果有裝甲車的話 你就朝它扔反坦克手雷
Opalka, you try a slow walk across here.
歐帕卡 在他開過來的時候 你嘗試著慢慢的過馬路
As he approaches, maybe you
can slow him down 也許你可以讓他在
before he takes the corner.
到路口之前就減速
Is that clear?
都明白嗎？
Yeah.
是的
Good luck.
祝大家好運
- All good? 一切都好嗎？
- Good. 沒問題
As we were trained.
就像我們訓練的一樣
Let's move!
大家行動吧！
Stop!
停！
Where were you, Curda?
你剛才在哪啊 庫達？
I didn't think that you were really
going to do it. 我之前並不認為你真的會動手
It's all over the radio. You shot him?
現在廣播裏到處都是你打中他了嗎？
The radio said 20,000 SS troops
廣播裏說 投入了2萬黨衛軍部隊
have been drafted in to look for us.
在搜捕我們
I need to get my family out of Prague.
我需要把我的家人弄出布拉格
No, Curda.
不行 庫達
No one is going anywhere, Curda.
任何人都不許動 庫達
You try and run now and they
will pick you up 你現在嘗試逃跑的話 他們會
before you reach the city limits.
在你逃出城之前把你抓住
You go home to your family, you stay calm,
you shut your mouth. 你現在回家 保持冷靜 把嘴閉緊
You think you can do that? Huh? Yeah.
你覺得你可以做到嗎？啊？好的
- We failed, Curda. 我們行動失敗了 庫達
- Failed? No. 失敗了？不要啊
We failed.
我們失敗了
Jan?
楊？
Jan.
楊
The Sten...
那個斯登衝鋒鎗...
I'm sorry.
我真的很對不起
Karl Frank has temporarily taken
Heydrich's place, 卡爾·法蘭克暫時取代了海德裏希的職位
and has proclaimed a state of emergency
and a curfew. 他宣佈全國進入緊急狀態 並實行宵禁
A reward of 10 million crowns will be given
for any information 任何提供線索 並致使罪犯落網的人
that leads to the arrest of the criminals.
將獲得一千萬克朗的獎勵
Anyone caught aiding the criminals
任何協助罪犯的人
will be shot, along with his entire family.
全家都會被槍斃
What went wrong out there?
你們剛才出了什麼問題？
We didn't even kill him.
我們根本就沒有殺掉他
Wounded.
受傷了
How bad?
有多嚴重？
It's hard to say.
這很難說
The SS still have the hospital surrounded,
黨衛軍仍然包圍著醫院
so presumably, he's still alive.
所以我猜他還活著
It seems like the Germans have more
men and guns up there 看起來德國人在這裏的軍隊和槍炮
than on the Eastern Front.
比在東線戰場都要多
They have taken several thousand hostages.
他們已經抓了好幾千的人質了
So, what do we do now?
所以 我們該怎麼做呢？
Nothing is leaving or entering Prague.
沒有東西現在能進出布拉格了
They are searching door to door.
他們正挨家挨戶的搜查
We have no safe houses left.
我們已經沒有藏身所了
So, where do we go?
那麼 我們該去那？
I've asked Father Vladimir Petrek.
我已經請求了神父弗拉基米爾·帕特裏克
He has agreed to hide 他同意了把所有
all the parachutists that are still
here in Prague 仍在布拉格的空降兵們都藏起來
until we can return you to London.
直到我們能把你們送回倫敦去
Wait here, a few hours.
在這裏等幾個小時
I will find a safe route to the cathedral.
我會找到一條去大教堂的安全線路
Hey.
喂
Tell me.
告訴我
Marie. Marie. Marie.
瑪利亞 瑪利亞
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
沒事的 沒事的
The Germans were rounding up hostages off
the street and... 德國人把人質們在路邊集攏起來然後...
She tried to escape.
她想要逃跑
It's okay.
沒事的
It's okay. It's okay.
沒事的 沒事的
- Josef 約瑟夫
- Jan! 楊！
Stop. Stop. Josef, stop.
住手 住手 約瑟夫 住手
- Stop! Josef. 住手！約瑟夫
- It's my fault. 都是我的錯
- Josef, it's not your fault. 約瑟夫不是你的錯
- It's my fault. 都怪我
Josef, listen to me!
約瑟夫 你聽我說！
- Listen to me. 你聽我說
- It's my fault. 都怪我
Stop! Listen to me. 住手！聽我說
Listen to me. 聽我說
You're risking the lives of everyone.
你這是在拿所有人的生命在冒險
For what? To shoot a few Germans?
為了什麼？ 就為了殺幾個德國鬼子？
She's gone. Josef, she's gone.
她不在了約瑟夫 她不在了
It's not your fault. Huh?
這不是你的錯啊？
It's my fault.
It's not your fault.
- It's my fault. 都是我的錯
- It's not your fault, Josef. 這不怪你 約瑟夫
It's not your fault, okay.
這不是你的錯 好嗎
I am sorry, Jan.
對不起 楊
I'm sorry, Marie.
對不起 瑪利亞
Mrs. Moravec, I'm sorry.
對不起 莫拉維斯太太
Hey.
喂
Hey, it's okay. It's okay.
喂 沒事的 沒事的
It's okay.
會沒事的
Father Petrek will meet you in there.
帕特裏克神父會在那見你
I'll send food with Ata. Go, go.
我會讓阿提亞來送方趕緊 趕緊
Thank you.
感謝你
I regret nothing.
我毫不後悔
You are the bravest men I have ever met.
你是我見過最勇敢的人
I'm Father Petrek. Welcome.
我是神父帕特裏克 歡迎
Please, come with me.
請跟我過來
This is our hidden crypt. You will
be safe there. 這是我們隱藏的地窖你在這裏會安全的
Thank you, Father.
感謝你 神父
You made it.
你做到了
Josef.
約瑟夫
Gentlemen.
先生們
This is Švarc, Bublik and Hruby.
這是施瓦茨 布布裏克和戶盧比
They are from the airdrop this spring.
他們是春天空投的那一批
Boredom may be the biggest enemy
we have here. 無聊也許現在是我們最大的敵人
I'm suggesting three men on guard duty
我建議隨時都要有三個人
in the nave balcony at all times.
在中殿的陽台值班
We rotate every six hours.
我們每6個小時輪換一班崗
These three take first watch.
你們三個人值頭班崗
I'm sorry it wasn't the outcome we
all hoped for. 很抱歉 這並不是我們當時想到的局面
None more than us.
除了我們 其他人也沒想到的
Reinhard Heydrich has died in hospital.
萊因哈德·海德裏希在醫院死掉了
A direct result of the injuries sustained
in the attack. 由襲擊造成的傷害直接導致的死亡
Yesterday, the Germans went to a
village, Lidice, 昨天 德國人去了一個叫裏迪斯的村子
and shot every man over the age of 16.
殺了每一個超過16歲的男子
The women and children have been
taken to camps, 婦女和孩子們被送去了集中營
and the buildings were razed to the ground.
房子都被夷為了平地
There has been talk that the village
aided you somehow. 有傳言說那個村子如何的幫助過你們
I've never even been to Lidice.
我從沒去過裏迪斯啊
These are dangerous times.
現在是恐怖的時期
Mere gossip wipes a whole village from the
face of the Earth. 僅僅是因為某些流言就能將一整個村子從地球上抹去
Today Karl Frank issued an amnesty
broadcast. 今天卡爾·法蘭克發表了一個特赦廣播
A full pardon for any person
and their family 任何透露刺客消息的人
in exchange for any information
about the assassins, 和其家人都將被無條件的赦免
even if they did not come forward before.
即使是他們之前沒有站出來
But there is a deadline of five days.
但是這有五天的有效期
After that, they plan to execute
30,000 Czechs. 在那之後 他們計劃處決3萬捷克人
- This must stop. 這必須被阻止
- What do you propose? 你有什麼建議嗎？
Me and Josef will go to a park,
我和約瑟夫會到一個公園去
place placards around our necks saying that
we killed Heydrich 在我們脖子上掛一個牌子寫著我們殺了海德裏希
and commit suicide.
然後就自殺
Jan. Stupid talk.
楊 別犯傻了
This is stupid talk.
這個主意太愚蠢了
As a soldier, 作為一個軍人
it is your duty to stay alive and
continue fighting. 你的責任是活著一直戰鬥下去
Do you understand that, Warrant
Officer Kubiš? 你明白嗎 庫比奇準尉？
The responsibility does not rest with you.
你死了德國人也不會停手的
We know who is responsible.
我們都知道這一切是誰的錯
They will have to answer eventually,
and they will. 他們最終一定會付出代價 會有那麼一天的
If I didn't believe that, I would not
be here now. 如果我沒有這樣的信念 我也不可能在這裏
Thank you, Father.
感謝你 神父
Ata.
阿提亞
Have you seen Marie?
你看到瑪利亞了嗎？
Is she well?
她還好嗎?
Beyond this brickwork and masonry,
在這些磚和石牆的外面
there is a large main sewer that
empties into the river. 有一條大的主下水管道通向河流
How do you know?
你怎麼知道？
I found some plans in Father Petrek's
office. 我在神父帕特裏克的辦公室裏找到了一些草圖
Now, if we can chisel through this, we have
a means of escape. 現在如果我們能把這裏鑿穿的話 我們就可以逃出去了
Escape to where?
往哪裏逃呢？
Well, until the British send plans
for our rescue, 好吧 直到英國派出援救計劃之前
we are stuck here.
我們算是困在這裏了
But should we be discovered, there
is no way out. 但是萬一我們被發現了 又衝不出去的話
I would like us at least to
have this option. 我希望至少我們能有條出路
We would then take our chances
in the streets. 我們逃出去之後就在街上碰碰運氣吧
Two men should be working here
at all times. 兩個人現在應該一直鑿了
What's her name?
她叫什麼名字？
Lenka.
蘭卡
Earlier, what Jan said...
早些時候 楊說的那些
About taking your own lives...
你們要自殺的話...
Was he serious?
他是認真的嗎?
Maybe.
也許吧
"Cowards die many times before
their deaths. "懦夫死前已死多次"
"The valiant never taste death but once."
"勇士一生只死一次"
Shakespeare.
莎士比亞.
You say you know the men 你說你知道是誰
who assassinated 刺殺了
Reichsprotektor Reinhard Heydrich,
帝國的衛士萊因哈德·海德裏希
but you didn't take part in it.
但是你並沒有參與其中
You say you don't know where they are,
你說你並不知道他們現在藏在哪裏
but you know the family who sheltered them.
但是你知道給他們提供庇護的那個家庭
No, please... Please, no.
請不要 請不要...
You walked in here on your own accord to
give us this statement. 你自願的走進來給我們這些信息
You say you are a true patriot and
the reason for doing that 你說你是真正的愛國者
is because you want to protect your family
這麼做的原因是為了保護你的家人
and for the killing of innocent
Czechs to stop. 和被無辜屠殺的捷克人民
And you say your name is...
你剛才說你叫什麼來著...
Karel Curda.
卡爾·庫達
Chalupsky.
恰拉普斯基
Ah!
哦！
Where are the parachutists?
空降兵們在哪？
I know nothing.
我什麼都不知道
You must be confusing us with other
Moravecs. 你們肯定把我們和其他叫莫拉維斯的人搞錯了
Where are the parachutists?
空降兵們在哪？
Please, let me clean myself up
before I leave. 請讓我走之前把自己整理一下
Go on, then.
好的 去吧
My son is a violinist.
我的兒子是一個小提琴演奏家
Tell them he knows nothing of this. Please.
請告訴他們他什麼都不知道
In the toilet.
在廁所裏
Something triggered it.
有些事出了岔子
Maybe other members of the church
found out. 也許是其他的神職人員發現我們了
Opalka. What did I miss?
歐帕卡我漏掉了哪裏？
Bishop Gorazd has talked to Father Petrek.
格拉德主教和帕特裏克神父談了談
Apparently our presence here is
endangering the church. 很顯然我們的存在讓教堂陷入了危險
He wants us to leave.
他希望我們離開
But Petrek has talked to Hajsky
但是帕特裏克神父告訴了海叔
and there is a plan to get us all out.
然後他們有一個把我們都轉移出去的計劃
When?
什麼時候?
Two in the coffins, 兩個裝在棺材裏
two under the dummy floors
兩個在裝在夾層
and the other three disguised
as pall bearers. 另外的三個人偽裝成抬棺人
That's the seven.
這一共七個人
How soon can you be ready?
你多久能準備好？
You like to play the violin.
你喜歡拉小提琴啊
Maybe you would like to see
your mother again. 也許你想要再見到你的母親
Yes, we managed to save her.
是的 我們想辦法把她保住了
No. No.
不要 不要啊
- No. - We saved her head.
不要 我們把她的腦袋保住了
Where are the assassins?
那些刺客在哪裏?
那些罪犯在哪裏?
Where are they hiding?
他們藏在哪裏?
Please stop.
請不要打了
Where are the assassins? Where
are they hiding? 那些刺客在哪裏? 他們藏在哪?
- Stop. -Where are they?
住手 他們在哪?
They're in the church.
他們在教堂
In the Cyril and Methodius Church.
在聖西裏爾&梅索蒂斯大教堂
The Germans are surrounding the church.
德國人正在包圍教堂
We have to warn the others.
我們必須警告其他人
No, no. There is no time.
不 不要去沒時間了
Take up defensive positions. We hold
them from here. 做好防禦準備我們在這裏拖住他們
Bublik, take the upper gallery.
布布裏克 去上面的走廊
Go back.
撤退
Back! Go back!
撤！快撤！
The church is surrounded. We have
to help them. 教堂被包圍了我們必須要幫他們
We must not give ourselves away, Josef.
我們不能白白出去送死 約瑟夫
Jan! Hey!
楊！嘿！
Jan! Keep quiet, please.
楊！請不要出聲
Block the stairwell.
把樓梯堵上
That's our only way out.
這是我們唯一出去的路
It's also the only way up.
這也是他們唯一能上來的路
Bublik!
布布裏克！
- I don't want to die.- Bublik, look at me.
我還不想死 布布裏克 看著我
- I don't want to die. -Breathe.
我還不想死 深呼吸
Breathe with me.
和我一起深呼吸
Big breath in. Big breath out.
深吸一口氣 全部呼出來
I don't want to die today. I don't
want to die today. 我今天還不想死 我今天還不想死
- I don't want to die today.
- As we were trained. 我今天還不想死 就像我們訓練的那樣
As we were trained. As we were trained.
就像我們訓練的那樣 就像我們訓練的那樣
Here. Look.
這裏 看好了
Nice and easy. Nice and easy.
別慌 慢慢來 別慌 慢慢來
Concentrate on the detail. Come on.
把注意力集中在細節上 來吧
- That's it. - I'm sorry, Jan.
就是這樣 對不起 楊
Okay?
好了嗎？
Nice and easy.
別慌 慢慢來
Yeah.
對
We're all here with you. And Czechoslovakia
is here with us. 我們幾個都和你在一起 整個捷克斯洛伐克就在我們的身旁
Cover the stairwell!
看好樓梯！
Bublik, the stairwell!
布布裏克 樓梯！
We've lost the stairwell!
我們失去了樓梯！
Stairs!
樓梯
I'm out!
我沒有子彈了！
Last one.
最後一個彈夾
Bublik!
布布裏克！
This is Jan Kubiš.
這是楊·克比奇
That's Adolf Opalka.
這是阿道夫·歐帕卡
And him, 這是他（約瑟夫）嗎？
I don't know, but it's not Josef Gabčik
or Valčik. 我不知道他是誰 但他不是約瑟夫·加布切克或者瓦切克
Wait. Wait.
等等 等等
Hruby, reload.
赫魯比 拿個新彈夾
You should get your friends to surrender.
你應該勸你的朋友們投降
Josef?
約瑟夫？
You should surrender now and
save yourselves. 你們現在應該投降來拯救自己
- There's Curda. - Do you hear me?
是庫達 你聽得見我嗎？
Curda! Curda!
庫達！ 庫達！
You will be treated humanely as
prisoners of war. 你們都會被像戰俘一樣的人道對待
We are Czechs.
我們是捷克人
We will never surrender!
我們決不投降！
Hey.
嘿
We save the last one...
我們把最後的一顆子彈...
For us.
留給自己
We dig! We dig!
我們趕緊挖！我們趕緊挖！
Keep digging! Don't stop!
一直挖！不要停！
凱撒大帝 - 莎士比亞
盛開在淪陷區那些爛漫的花朵
一朵朵的消逝在了戰爭的陰雲裏
雖千萬人, 吾往矣
約瑟夫·加布切克
楊·克比奇
阿道夫·歐帕卡
約瑟夫·瓦切克
加羅斯拉夫·施瓦茨
約瑟夫·布布裏克
楊·戶盧比
這七位空降兵直到最後一刻 在教堂堅守了6個小時
總共有大約超過5000名捷克的男女老幼受到了
海德裏希刺殺行動的牽連 遭到了黨衛軍的處決
萊因哈德·海德裏希被認為直接主導並且執行了
歐洲的猶太滅絕計劃
他是納粹德國在戰時被刺殺的最高級將領
在因刺殺行動引起的納粹對無辜平民進行的報復行動之後
溫斯頓·丘吉爾宣佈慕尼黑協定完全的作廢
並且將捷克斯洛伐克視作為自由而戰的重要同盟